(Yoon Chan Young)
"(يون تشان يونغ)"
(Bong Jae Hyun)
"(بونغ جاي هيون)"
(Special Appearance, Lee Seo Jin)
"ظهور خاص، (لي سو جين)"
(Lee Kyoung Young, Seo Tae Hwa, Hwang Bo Ra)
"(لي كيونغ يونغ) (سو تاي هوا)، (هوانغ بو را)"
(Lee Hee Jin, Won Tae Min, Ko Dong Wook, Joo Yoon Chan)
"(لي هي جين)، (وون تاي مين) (كو دونغ ووك)، (جو يون تشان)"
(High School Return of a Gangster)
"انتقام طالب"
Did I make you surprise?
هل فاجأتكِ؟
I'm Seo Chil Sung.
أنا (سو تشيل سونغ)
I'm a brother of Yi Heon's father, Kim Deuk Pal.
أنا أخ والد (يي هيون)، (كيم ديوك بال)
I think you've got the wrong person.
أعتقد أنك مخطئ
I'm sure he is Song Yi Heon.
أنا واثق أنه (سونغ يي هيون)
Do you want to deny that he's Deuk Pal's son?
هل تنكرين أنه ابن (ديوك بال)؟
Or are you keeping it a secret so that no one can know...
أم أنكِ تبقين الأمر سراً حتى لا يعرف أحد...
he's not Chairman Bae's son?
أنه ليس ابن الرئيس (باي)؟
No. I don't know who Deuk Pal is.
لا، أنا لا أعرف من هو (ديوك بال)
Is it true...
هل صحيح...
that you just got out of a drug addiction?
أنكِ تعافيتِ من اعتياد الدواء مؤخراً؟
He prevented you from getting kidnapped.
حماكِ من الاختطاف
He was a victim of school violence,
كان ضحية العنف المدرسي
but he was named as the bully instead.
ولكنه لُقب بالمتنمر رغم ذلك
So he went to the police station and the prosecutors' office.
لذا ذهب إلى مركز الشرطة ومكتب الادعاء
With all that going on, he's still here to take care of you.
مع ذلك كله، بقي هنا للاعتناء بكِ
Did you know about all those?
هل كنتِ تعرفين ذلك؟
Parents have to be...
يجب أن يكون الآباء...
Parents have to be guards.
يجب أن يكون الآباء حراساً
The guards who protect their children.
الحراس الذين يحمون أطفالهم
The children without these guards...
الأطفال من دون هؤلاء الحراس...
are destined to be unfortunate.
قُدر لهم سوء الحظ
Learning to live alone early in life doesn't do any good.
تعلم الاعتماد على الذات مبكراً في الحياة ليس أمراً جيداً
Get a hold of yourself.
استجمعي قواكِ
If you don't,
إن لم تفعلي...
you might also lose your kid.
قد تخسرين ابنكِ أيضاً
Do you get that?
هل فهمتِ؟
What is our nephew doing?
ماذا يفعل ابن أخينا؟
Children are sleepyheads.
إنه نائم
Yes. They say kids like to sleep.
نعم، يُقال إن الأطفال يحبون النوم
How old is he again?
مجدداً، كم عمره؟
Yi Heon is 19 years old.
إنه في التاسعة عشرة
That means it was 19 years ago.
هذا يعني أنه حدث قبل ذلك
Deuk Pal was in Gangwon Province 19 years ago.
كان (ديوك بال) في مقاطعة (غانغوون) في ذلك الوقت
So there weren't any girls around him.
لذا لم تكن حوله أي فتيات
If he saw an actress,
لو أنه قابل ممثلة...
I would have remembered.
لتذكرت ذلك
(High School Return of a Gangster)
"انتقام طالب"
I told you that I wouldn't mention your name.
قلت إنني لن أذكر اسمك
Couldn't you understand what I said?
ألم تفهم ما قلته؟
What the heck are you doing right now?
ماذا تفعل هنا الآن؟
Can't you tell?
ألا تعرف؟
I'm stabbing in the back.
أنا أطعن في الظهر
In these punks' backs.
في حقائب هؤلاء الحمقى
- Hey. - There's a tablet PC.
- مهلاً - هناك حاسب محمول
Its password is 808706.
كلمة السر هي 808706
Hey, take it away from him. If he opens it, we're doomed.
خذوه منه، سيُقضى علينا إن فتحه
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعلون؟
Yes. I'm Chief Prosecutor Choi Myung Hyun.
نعم، أنا المدعي العام (تشوي ميونغ هيون)
Send security guards to the Investigation Room 1002.
أرسل رجال الأمن إلى غرفة التحقيق 1002
- Hey, Park Duk Jun! - What?
- (بارك دوك جون)! - ماذا؟
- Darn it. - You crazy punk.
- بئساً - أيها المجنون الأحمق
Come on out.
اخرج
(Song Yi Heon, Yoo Moon Soo, Lee Byung Heon)
"(سونغ يي هيون) (يو مون سو)، (لي بيونغ هيون)"
(Song Yi Heon)
"(سونغ يي هيون)"
Are you filming this right now?
"هل تصور هذا الآن؟"
Did you harass...
هل ضايقت...
all the kids on here?
الأطفال جميعهم هنا؟
Eat it already.
"كله حالاً"
Chew it.
امضغه
Chew and swallow it.
امضغه وابتلعه
I'm the assailant.
أنا هو المعتدي
With them, I beat up Song Yi Heon,
ضربت (سونغ يي هيون) معهم
mugged, and harassed him.
صورته، وضايقته
Yi Heon jumped off the pedestrian overpass...
قفز (يي هيون) من جسر المشاة...
because of me.
بسببي
Why did you do this?
فعلت هذا؟
I was the only one who knew he carried his tablet PC in his bag.
كنت الوحيد الذي يعرف أنه يحمل حاسوبه في حقيبته
In other words,
بمعنى آخر...
no one could reveal you were a victim except for me.
لم يستطع أحد غيري إظهار أنك الضحية
If the truth wasn't revealed,
إن لم تُكشف الحقيقة...
that pervert would have kept bragging about it like a war trophy.
سيواصل ذلك المختل التفاخر بالأمر وكأنه غنيمة حرب
No.
لا
Why didn't you listen to me?
لماذا لم تستمع إلي؟
I said I'd give you a chance.
قلت إنني سأمنحك فرصة
Your father started the instalment savings.
بدأ والدك الادخار بالتقسيط
I gave you a chance to use it, but why did you throw it away?
أعطيتك فرصة لاستخدامه، لمَ تخلصت منه؟
It felt gross that you were going to be put behind bars.
شعرت بالأسى لأنك ستُسجن
I despise Se Kyung, but he was right.
كرهت (سي كيونغ)، ولكنه محق
When I see those punks,
عندما أرى هؤلاء الحمقى
I can see why guilty ones should get punished.
أفهم لمَ يجب أن يُعاقب المذنبون
And this way, I'll feel less unfortunate.
وبهذه الطريقة، أشعر بسوء أقل
You punk.
أيها الأحمق
Why did you feed me?
لمَ أطعمتني؟
I gave you a chance.
لقد منحتك فرصة
This wouldn't have happened...
ما كان هذا ليحدث
if you withdrew the complaint and apologized sincerely.
لو أنك سحبت الشكوى، واعتذرت بصدق
Are we really...
هل...
getting expelled?
سنُطرد حقاً؟
That lady's lawyer will help us, right?
سيساعدنا محامي تلك السيدة، صحيح؟
Do you have the lawyer's number?
هل تملك رقمه؟
I called him earlier,
اتصلت به سابقاً
but the lawyer said he was pulling out.
ولكن المحامي قال إنه سينسحب
Why is he making a fuss when the rest were quiet? Seriously!
لم أحدث ضجة بينما يلتزم البقية الصمت؟ بئساً!
Song Yi Heon, he'll be half-dead when I get out of here.
سأقضي على (سونغ يي هيون) عندما أخرج من هنا
If you ever touch him, you're all dead meat.
ستصبح جثة هامدة إن لمسته
Darn it.
بئساً
Why can't I reach you?
"لمَ لا أستطيع الاتصال بك؟"
Your mother is going through the discharge procedure,
"تقوم والدتك في إجراءات الخروج"
saying that she'll receive treatment as an outpatient.
"وقالت إنها ستتلقى العلاج في الخارج"
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف
(Emergency transport, Ministry of Justice)
"نقل الطوارئ، وزارة العدل"
Apologize.
اعتذر
Why do I have to apologize?
لمَ يجب أن أعتذر؟
Because you made Yi Heon an assailant...
لأنك جعلت (يي هيون) المعتدي
and made him nervous by sending him here.
وأزعجته بإرساله إلى هنا
I didn't mention it to him, but you almost blackmailed him.
لم أخبره بالأمر ولكنك كنت تبتزه تقريباً
Apologize to him.
اعتذر إليه
Song Yi Heon might be a victim of this case.
قد يكون (سونغ يي هيون) ضحية في هذه القضية
But what he did to you makes him an assailant.
ولكن ما فعله بك يجعله معتدياً
I made myself clear.
قلت بوضوح
That you should stay away from him to live a decent life.
إن عليك الابتعاد عنه لتعيش حياة لائقة
We moved here because they said...
انتقلنا إلى هنا لأنهم قالوا
it had a good school district, but it wasn't true.
إن هناك مدرسة جيدة، ولكن هذا غير صحيح
I should have sent you to a private high school...
كان عليّ إرسالك إلى مدرسة خاصة
so that you could make better friends with similar backgrounds.
حتى تكون صداقات أفضل من طبقة تشبهنا
Darn it.
بئساً!
Okay. You'll transfer to another school at once!
حسناً، ستنتقل إلى مدرسة أخرى حالاً!
I'm not going to another school.
لن أذهب إلى مدرسة أخرى
If you force me,
إن أجبرتني على ذلك...
I'll drop out of school.
سأترك المدرسة
I'll study by myself.
سأدرس بمفردي
Also, I'll continue to be friends with Yi Heon.
وسأتابع صداقتي مع (يي هيون)
For goodness' sake.
بئساً
Do you want to get kicked out? Do you want us to abandon you?
هل تريد أن تُطرد؟ هل تريدنا أن نهجرك؟
You might abandon me,
يمكنك أن تهجرني...
but I won't abandon you.
ولكنني لن أهجرك
I'll grow up to be an honourable, honest adult,
سأكبر وأصبح رجلاً شريفاً وصادقاً
who won't shame you, so keep watching me.
شخصاً لا يحرجك، لذا شاهدني
To do so, I have to take the afternoon class.
يجب أن أحضر الدروس المسائية لفعل ذلك
(Hyunwoo University Hospital)
"مشفى جامعة (هيونوو)"
Hey, our nephew. We're here.
يا ابن أخينا، نحن هنا
Boss.
أيها الزعيم
Wait.
مهلاً
I heard you had surgery.
سمعت أنك خضعت إلى جراحة
Which area did you get operated on? Are you okay now?
في أي منطقة أُجريت؟ هل أنت بخير؟
I'm okay.
أنا بخير
We get stabbed all the time, you know.
نحن نُطعن طوال الوقت كما تعلم
This is the problem.
هذه هي المشكلة
You hurt your shoulders before.
لقد أصبت كتفيك سابقاً
And you also hurt your head...
ثم أنك أصبت رأسك
while fighting in Gangneung. You laughed it out...
في أثناء القتال في (غانغنيونغ) وكنت تضحك...
while getting treated and taking medication.
في أثناء العلاج وتناول الدواء
This is why we can't assist you properly.
لهذا لا يمكننا خدمتك على نحو صحيح
You lost weight too. In fact, you look starving.
ثم أنك خسرت الوزن تبدو وكأنك تتضور جوعاً
I've never been this heavy in my life, though.
لم يزد وزني إلى هذه الدرجة من قبل
By the way,
بالمناسبة...
have we ever met personally before?
هل التقينا شخصياً من قبل؟
My father said...
قال أبي...
he was like a father to him.
إنك بمكانة الأب له
Why did you leave the field?
لمَ تركت المجال؟
The Chilsung Gang without you...
من دونك، عصابة (تشيلسونغ)...
isn't the Chilsung Gang, is it?
لن تكون موجودة، صحيح؟
I can see why they say you were his son.
فهمت لمَ قالوا إنك ابنه
I went up to the ward to see you.
ذهبت إلى القسم لرؤيتك
And your mother...
ووالدتك...
was waiting for the doctor...
كانت تنتظر الطبيب
for the last consultation before she leaves.
من أجل استشارة أخيرة قبل مغادرتها
I think we have some time.
أعتقد أن لدينا بعض الوقت
Have a seat.
اجلس
We'll wait outside.
سننتظر في الخارج
When I was lying in bed for a week after the surgery,
بينما كنت مستلقياً في السرير لأسبوع بعد الجراحة...
all of a sudden,
فجأة...
I got scared of fighting.
شعرت بالخوف من الشجار
If a gangster gets afraid, it's over for him.
إن شعر رجل العصابة بالخوف فسينتهي أمره
Maybe that was why...
ربما لهذا السبب
I hurried to pass down the Chilsung Gang to Deuk Pal.
أسرعت في التنازل عن عصابة (تشيلسونغ) لـ (ديوك بال)
Right.
نعم
If Deuk Pal was still here, our Chilsung Gang would be...
لو كان (ديوك بال) هنا لكانت عصابتنا...
But he is not here, is he?
ولكنه ليس هنا، صحيح؟
You should let him go.
عليك نسيانه
When I...
عندما...
first heard of Deuk Pal's son, I thought it was ridiculous.
سمعت عن ابن (ديوك بال) للمرة الأولى، اعتقدت أنها سخافة
He was the one who made a scene at Deuk Pal's funeral.
إنه الشخص الذي أحدث جلبة في جنازة (ديوك بال)
Still,
ومع ذلك...
I came with the thought of checking him myself.
قررت التحقق من الأمر بنفسي
When I met you,
عندما التقيتك...
I found it even more ridiculous.
عرفت أن الأمر أكثر سخافة
Look.
اسمع
I tried to find a resemblance.
حاولت أن أجد تشابهاً
But you look nothing like him.
ولكنك لا تشبهه مطلقاً
I thought my boys were being fooled by a kid.
اعتقدت أن طفلاً قد خدع رجالي
I carry all sorts of talismans in my wallet.
أنا أحمل جميع أنواع التمائم في محفظتي
In spring, I pay tribute in a temple.
في الربيع، أدفع جزية في المعبد
I believe in folk religions, ghosts, and superstitions.
أنا أؤمن بالعادات التقليدية الأشباح، والخوارق
But...
ولكن...
I...
أنا...
I don't know...
لا أعلم...
if I should be sad or happy...
إن كان يجب أن أفرح أو أحزن...
about feeling your presence...
لأنني أشعر بوجودك...
momentarily like this.
لحظياً هكذا
He knows that I'm Kim Deuk Pal.
إنه يعرف أنني (كيم ديوك بال)
We need to...
يجب علينا...
let go of the dead and move on.
أن ننسى الأموات، ونواصل حياتنا
I stayed until now...
بقيت حتى الآن...
only to protect this young kid.
لحماية هذا الفتى فقط
Right.
نعم
Wasn't it because you wanted to go to school?
أليس السبب هو أنك أردت دخول المدرسة؟
By the way, are you getting good scores?
بالمناسبة، هل تحصل على درجات جيدة؟
I'm somewhere between Grade 4 and Grade 5.
أنا في مكان ما بين المستويين الرابع والخامس
If you couldn't get good grades when you did nothing but studying,
إن لم تنل درجات جيدة بينما لم تفعل شيئاً سوى الدراسة
you're just not bright.
فهذا يعني أنك لست ذكياً فحسب
Sir.
سيدي
It isn't easy to get a Grade One.
ليس من السهل الوصول إلى المستوى الأول
Is that so?
حقاً؟
For me,
بالنسبة إلي...
Deuk Pal was always Grade 1.
كان (ديوك بال) في المركز الأول دائماً
It feels like...
أشعر أنني...
I'm losing my man twice.
خسرت الرجل مرتين
Did something happen between you and our nephew?
هل حدث شيء بينك وبين ابن أخينا؟
You stay here and help Deuk Pal.
ابقيا هنا وساعدا (ديوك بال)
Take your time.
خذا وقتكما
Why do you keep on insisting?
لمَ الإصرار؟
She can't, right?
لا يمكنها، صحيح؟
She'll be in big trouble if she goes home now, right?
ستقع في مشكلة كبيرة إن عادت الآن، صحيح؟
Didn't you just hear him?
ألم تسمعيه تواً؟
This hospital's psychiatric clinic doesn't allow long-term stay,
لا تسمح العيادة النفسية بإقامة طويلة
but they took me in...
ولكنهم قبلوني
because Yi Heon begged them about it so much.
لأن (يي هيون) توسل إليهم كثيراً
He said I should get discharged from the hospital.
قال إن عليّ الخروج من المشفى
Also,
ثم أنني...
I did get much better.
تحسنت كثيراً
I don't know. You can't leave.
لا أعلم، لا يمكنكِ المغادرة
Whatever. You go ahead and live here, then.
أياً يكن، يمكنكِ العيش هنا
I'm leaving.
سأغادر
Tell her that I can go home.
أخبرها أنني أستطيع العودة إلى المنزل
Even the doctor said it was okay,
حتى الطبيب قال إن لا بأس في ذلك
but she just wouldn't let me go.
ولكنها لا تسمح لي بالذهاب
Yi Heon, she'll be in big trouble if she goes home now, right?
(يي هيون)، ستقع في مشكلة كبيرة إن ذهبت الآن، صحيح؟
Is it okay for her to go home?
هل يمكنها الذهاب إلى المنزل؟
She got much better.
لقد تحسنت كثيراً
She still needs to be treated for a while,
يجب أن تُعالج لفترة
so you can come and see the doctor.
لذا يمكنكِ مراجعة الطبيب
It's important for her to register at a rehab centre...
من المهم أن تدخل مركز إعادة تأهيل
to beat the temptation...
لتتغلب على الرغبة
by talking a lot to the survivors...
عبر التحدث كثيراً إلى الناجين
who have overcome the addiction.
الذين تغلبوا على الاعتياد
Okay. Please discharge her, then.
حسناً، أخرجها من فضلك
I'm going home.
سأذهب إلى المنزل
What if Lee Mi Kyung, that crazy witch, comes for you?
ماذا إن جاءت المجنونة (لي مي كيونغ) إليك؟
How can I stop her when she wants to go home so much?
كيف أمنعها إن أرادت العودة إلى المنزل بشدة؟
Also, she'll have to return to society one day.
وعليها العودة إلى المجتمع يوماً ما
I'll try my best to take care of the issue regarding Mi Kyung.
سأبذل جهدي لحل مشكلة (مي كيونغ)
Why is he taking so long?
ما الذي يؤخره؟
It was Mr. Kim's day off today.
إنه يوم عطلة السيد (كيم)
It must take some time for him to get ready.
يحتاج بعض الوقت ليستعد
There's a girl, for sure.
هناك فتاة بالتأكيد
When a man has a girlfriend, he speaks softly.
يتحدث الرجل بلطف عندما يحظى بحبيبة
On top of that, you looked me in the eye...
بالإضافة إلى ذلك، نظرت في عيني
while speaking coherently.
بينما تتحدث بثبات
Who is this girl?
من تلك الفتاة؟
You are the one who should become independent from Father...
أنتِ من عليها الاستقلال عن أبي
and meet a nice guy.
ومقابلة شاب لطيف
I stayed home for 20 years.
بقيت في المنزل لعشرين عاماً
It's been more than 20 years since I made money myself.
مر أكثر من عشرين عاماً منذ جنيت المال بنفسي
Also, you need to go to college.
كما أن عليك دخول الجامعة
- If I leave him now... - This is why...
- إن تركته الآن... - لهذا...
you and Song Yi Heon...
أنتِ و(سونغ يي هيون)
couldn't say anything while suffering from Mi Kyung.
لم تقولا أي شيء بينما تعانيان بسبب (مي كيونغ)
Think about it.
فكري في الأمر
Will Chairman Bae come to Yi Heon's graduation?
هل سيحضر الرئيس (باي) تخرج (يي هيون)؟
Do you think he's a guy...
هل تعتقدين أنه الرجل...
who will sit on the father's seat at Yi Heon's wedding?
الذي سيجلس في مقعد الأب في زفاف (يي هيون)؟
He didn't even register Yi Heon as his son.
لم يسجل (يي هيون) كإبن له حتى
In times of trouble, he wasn't by your side...
في أوقات الأزمات، لم يكن في جانبكِ...
or listened to you. Then he's not your family, is he?
ولم يستمع إليكِ لهذا لا يُعتبر عائلتكِ، صحيح؟
Consider becoming independent from him.
فكري في الاستقلال عنه
You can do it.
يمكنكِ فعلها
Why isn't he coming?
لماذا لم يأت بعد؟
Do you want to grab a cab instead?
هل نأخذ سيارة أجرة؟
(Participating in Berlin Build Expo, OK Construction)
"شارك في معرض بناء (برلين) (أو كي) للبناء"
Yi Heon.
(يي هيون)
You can go first. I'm going to go and see Chairman Bae.
اذهبي أولاً، سأذهب إلى رؤية الرئيس (باي)
Think about how you could be independent.
فكري في طريقة للاستقلال
Please take her home.
أوصلها إلى المنزل
How are you going to see him?
كيف ستقابله؟
You can't even reach him.
لا يمكنك الاتصال به حتى
I think I know where to find him, so I'm going to go and check.
أعتقد أنني أعرف أين أجده سأتحقق من ذلك
Goodness.
عجباً
Yi Heon!
(يي هيون)!
To the airport, please.
إلى المطار من فضلك
(Privacy Mode, Accept, Decline, On Hold)
"وضع الخصوصية، قبول، رفض، انتظار"
Where are you?
"أين أنتما؟"
Actually, we talked to the guys about the future...
في الواقع، ناقشنا المستقبل مع الرجال
and sent off some.
وتخلصنا من بعضهم
We are on our way to meet you. Where are you?
نحن في طريقنا لرؤيتك، أين أنت؟
Come to the airport. Chairman Bae was in Berlin.
تعاليا إلى المطار كان الرئيس (باي) في (برلين)
We can get Lee Mi Kyung once we see Chairman Bae, right?
يمكننا إيجاد (لي مي كيونغ) حالما نرى الرئيس (باي)، صحيح؟
How did you find out?
كيف اكتشفت الأمر؟
We couldn't find him though we tried so hard.
لم نستطع إيجاده، رغم محاولاتنا
(Participating in Berlin Build Expo, OK Construction)
"شارك في معرض بناء (برلين) (أو كي) للبناء"
He will land in an hour.
سيهبط بعد ساعة
Push the gas hard to get to the airport within an hour.
أسرعا لتصلا إلى المطار خلال ساعة
Let's meet with Chairman Bae...
"لنقابل الرئيس (باي)"
and put an end to Lee Mi Kyung.
ونضع حداً لـ (لي مي كيونغ)
- Yes, sir! - Let's go.
- نعم، سيدي! - هيا بنا
Se Kyung.
(سي كيونغ)
Why isn't Yi Heon coming to school?
لمَ لا يأتي (يي هيون) إلى المدرسة؟
Well, actually...
حسناً، في الواقع...
Don't tell me...
لا تقل
he's trying to avoid apologizing to Min Ji.
إنه يحاول تجنب الاعتذار إلى (مين جي)
Why isn't he coming after saying her face is big?
لماذا لم يأت بعد قوله إن وجهها سمين؟
Your face is not big. You know that, right?
إن وجهكِ ليس سميناً أنتِ تعرفين هذا، صحيح؟
Actually...
في الواقع...
Please come closer.
اقتربن
Yi Heon was investigated by the prosecution.
إن الادعاء يحقق مع (يي هيون)
What?
ماذا؟
Was it because Byung Chul's clan filed a complaint?
هل السبب هو شكوى عائلة (بيونغ تشول)؟
Our teacher said he was absent due to a family issue.
قالت معلمتنا إنه غائب بسبب مشكلات عائلية
- Was that a pure lie, then? - Gosh.
- هل كانت تلك كذبة؟ - عجباً
How's Yi Heon?
كيف حال (يي هيون)؟
Is he all right?
هل هو بخير؟
Yes. Thanks to Jae Min's help.
نعم، بفضل مساعدة (جاي مين)
I'm jealous of Yi Heon.
أنا أحسد (يي هيون)
He has friends like you who worry about him.
إن له صديقات مثلكن يقلقن عليه
So how did it turn out?
كيف انتهى الأمر؟
Was Jae Min's help no use?
ألم تكن مساعدة (جاي مين) مفيدة؟
Did Yi Heon get arrested?
هل قُبض على (يي هيون)؟
No. He is the victim.
لا، إنه الضحية
The assailants were arrested.
قُبض على المعتدين
Yi Heon told me he wouldn't come to school...
أخبرني (يي هيون) أنه لن يأتي إلى المدرسة
to visit his mother in the hospital.
ليزور والدته في المشفى
By the way,
بالمناسبة...
why did Jae Min help Yi Heon?
لمَ ساعد (جاي مين) (يي هيون)؟
I know. He bullied Yi Heon all the time.
نعم، كان يتنمر عليه طوال الوقت
Why help him now?
لم يساعده الآن؟
This is the Prosecutors' Office. My workplace.
هذا مكتب الادعاء، مكان عملي
How dare you get into a fight here?
كيف تجرؤ على الشجار هنا؟
Were you born to humiliate me?
هل ولدت لإهانتي؟
Come, everyone.
تعالوا جميعاً
(Prosecutor's Room)
"غرفة الادعاء"
Follow me.
اتبعني
Why didn't you listen to me?
"لماذا لم تستمع إلي؟"
I said I'd give you a chance.
"قلت إنني سأمنحك فرصة"
Your father started the instalment savings.
"بدأ والدك الادخار بالتقسيط"
I gave you a chance to use it, but why did you throw it away?
أعطيتك فرصة لاستخدامه، لمَ تخلصت منه؟
I know. He got bullied so much, but...
نعم، تعرض إلى التنمر بشدة
Have you ever had a friend...
هل كان لديكن صديق؟
who suddenly felt like a grown-up?
شعرتن فجأة أنه أصبح راشداً؟
That their personality and how they speak changed completely...
وأن شخصيته وطريقة كلامه تغيرتا كلياً
like a different person?
وكأنه شخص مختلف؟
As if they have a dual personality.
وكأن له شخصية مزدوجة؟
Have you had anyone like that?
هل قابلتن شخصاً كهذا؟
- I have. - Me too.
- نعم - وأنا أيضاً
You know Ji A from Class A, right?
هل تعرف (جي آه) من الصف (أي)؟
She has a dual personality.
إن لها شخصية مزدوجة
When she's with us, she's such an extrovert.
تكون منفتحة جداً عندما تكون معنا
But when she goes out with someone, she turns into an introvert.
ولكنها تصبح انطوائية عندما تخرج مع أحدهم
That's dual personality, right?
إنها شخصية مزدوجة، صحيح؟
Byun Ji Hye, the popular one who sang at the school festival.
(بيون جي هاي)، المشهور الذي غنى في مهرجان المدرسة
Wonder of Born Boys is the same. He has a severe dual personality.
(ووندر أوف بورن بويز) كذلك الأمر، لديه فصام حاد
But it's not just on a special occasion or to a specific person.
ولكن ليس في المناسبات الخاصة أو مع شخص محدد
What if they are like that to everyone in every situation?
ماذا إن كان هكذا مع الجميع في كل وقت؟
He looks just like the one I know from the outside,
إنه يبدو كشخص أعرفه من الخارج
but he talks and behaves like a different person.
ولكنه يتحدث ويتصرف كشخص مختلف
That's not a dual personality. That's being possessed.
هذه ليست شخصية مزدوجة، بل إنه ممسوس
I know well about it because I'm into "DOD" these days.
أعرف هذا جيداً لأنني أقرأ (نون ألف ميم) هذه الأيام
"DOD."
(نون ألف ميم)
It's a web-based novel called "Debut or Die."
إنها رواية إلكترونية تُدعى (نفذ أو مت)
I see.
فهمت
The soul who couldn't leave behind the way he spoke...
الروح التي لا يمكنها ترك طريقة كلامها
and his lifestyle and behaviour...
ونمط حياتها وتصرفاتها
goes into someone else's body...
تدخل جسد شخص آخر
and lives with that body.
وتعيش في ذلك الجسد
That soul can really be that of an adult, then.
يمكن أن تكون تلك الروح لشخص بالغ إذاً
That's right.
هذا صحيح
Like in "DOD,"
مثل (نون ألف ميم)
an ordinary student who failed the national exam...
تلميذ عادي فشل في الامتحان الوطني
wakes up to find himself as an idol.
يستيقظ ليجد نفسه فناناً
Or an ordinary employee suddenly becomes a prince of a divine land.
أو موظف عادي يصبح أمير أرض مقدسة فجأة
That means a grown-up can be a kid too.
هذا يعني أن البالغ قد يصبح طفلاً أيضاً
Does it make its title,
هل يُسمى هذا...
"High School Return..."
"عودة البالغ"...
"of a Grown-Up?"
"إلى المدرسة الثانوية"؟
No. If he's an ordinary grown-up, it's no fun.
لا، وكأنه بالغ عادي، هذا غير ممتع
Well...
حسناً...
What if a grown-up gangster becomes a high school kid?
ماذا إن أصبح رجل عصابات تلميذاً في الثانوية؟
- What? - Nice.
- ماذا؟ - هذا رائع
"High School Return of a Gangster."
"انتقام طالب"
- Nice. Yes. - Sounds fun, right?
- يبدو ممتعاً، صحيح؟
I like it.
أحببته
By the way, who got possessed?
بالمناسبة، من هو الممسوس؟
Goodness. Whenever I smell the scent of Korea,
عجباً! عندما أشم رائحة (كوريا)
I crave seolleongtang with lots of kkakdugi in it.
أشتهي حساء عظام الثور مع الكثير من الفجل
Mr. Jeon, since you won one contract,
سيد (جون)، بما أنك ربحت العقد
have one piece of kkakdugi.
تناول قطعة من الفجل
Mr. Goo, you also won one contract, but it was a significant deal.
سيد (غو)، ربحت عقداً أيضاً ولكنها صفقة رابحة
So you can have all the kkakdugi you want.
لذا يمكنك تناول ما أردت من الفجل
Thank you, sir.
شكراً لك، سيدي
I'll keep an eye on how much kkakdugi you eat.
سأراقب كمية الفجل التي تتناولها
Girls, you can eat whatever you want as much as you want.
يا فتيات، يمكنكن تناول ما تردن
At the Gate One...
في البوابة الأولى...
(Lawyer Park)
"المحامي (بارك)"
How did it go with Song Yi Heon?
ما أخبار (سونغ يي هيون)؟
Were those students the assailants?
"هل كان التلاميذ هم المعتدون؟"
One kid made a testimony.
"قدم أحد التلاميذ إفادته"
I told you not to let him walk free.
طلبت منك ألا تدعه حراً
Then that punk will...
ذلك الأحمق...
He will put me in jail.
سيرميني في السجن
Of course, he walks free. He's the victim.
"إنه حر بالتأكيد، إنه الضحية"
I'm not going to defend them, so don't call me.
"لن أدافع عنهم لذا لا تتصلي بي"
Gosh. I made myself clear...
كان كلامي واضحاً
and told them to get rid of any problems.
طلبت منهم التخلص من أي مشكلة
The Dongsoo Gang and those school punks...
عصابة (دونغسو) وهؤلاء التلاميذ الحمقى
are both useless.
كلاهما عديم الفائدة
Mi Kyung, which seolleongtang place are we going?
(مي كيونغ)، إلى أي مطعم حساء سنذهب؟
I don't think she'll be able to find a place.
لا أعتقد أنها ستجد مطعماً
Because she'll get busy soon.
لأنها ستكون مشغولة قريباً
What's wrong with him?
ما خطبه؟
Sir.
سيدي
The Chinese food is good around here, not seolleongtang.
الطعام الصيني شهي هنا، وليس الحساء
So, do you care to join me in having a bowl of jjamppong...
هل تريد مشاركتي طبقاً من (جامبونغ)...
in a quiet room?
في غرفة هادئة؟
You.
أنت...
You, Song Yi Heon.
أنت (سونغ يي هيون)
Instead of calling me, "Song Yi Heon,"
بدلاً من مناداتي (سونغ يي هيون)
you should call me "Son," shouldn't you?
يجب أن تناديني "يا بني"، صحيح؟
Chairman Bae...
أيها الرئيس (باي)...
of OK Construction.
من (أو كي) للبناء
I can explain everything to Chairman Bae later.
سأشرح كل شيء للرئيس لاحقاً
He'll understand me.
سيفهمني
He's not going to abandon me, is he?
لن يتخلى عني، صحيح؟
Gosh. For goodness' sake!
بئساً!
When I saw you five years ago, you looked like a skinny beggar.
عندما رأيتك قبل خمس سنوات كنت تبدو كمتسول نحيل
Did you get a makeover somewhere?
هل غيرت شكلك في مكان ما؟
I have always looked good in any clothes.
كنت أبدو جيداً في أي ملابس أرتديها
I guess you've never observed Yi Heon right.
أعتقد أنك لم تمعن النظر في (يي هيون) قط
It sounds like you're blaming me.
أشعر وكأنك تلومني
I think I've been nothing but good to you.
أعتقد أنني لم أفعل سوى الخير لك
"Jirokwima."
(جيروكويما)
What?
ماذا؟
It's as if you're pointing at a deer and saying it is a horse.
إنه تعني النظر إلى غزال وقول إنه حصان
You're insisting that you're a father when you're not.
أنت تصر على أنك أب بينما لست ذلك
Haven't you heard that Song Yi Heon had become...
ألم تسمع أن (سونغ يي هيون)
an assailant of school violence, that he called your company...
مُتهم بالعنف المدرسي وأنه اتصل بشركتك...
so many times, and that the police are looking...
عدة مرات، وأن الشرطة تبحث...
for his father?
عن والده؟
Mi Kyung will handle them.
ستتولى (مي كيونغ) أمرهم
Sir.
سيدي
Do you know what kind of person she is?
هل تعرف أي نوع من الأشخاص هي؟
She drugged my mother...
جعلت والدتي تعتاد الأدوية
and made Yi Heon an assailant of school violence case.
وجعلت (يي هيون) مُتهماً في قضية عنف مدرسي
To take your legal wife's place once she dies,
لتحل محل زوجتك الشرعية عندما تموت
she ordered gangsters to kidnap my mother.
أمرت رجال عصابة باختطاف والدتي
What are you talking about?
ما الذي تتحدث عنه؟
Sir, those are all lies!
سيدي، إنها أكاذيب!
It doesn't make sense.
هذا غير منطقي
How would I dare to hurt your son?
كيف سأجرؤ على أذية ابنك؟
While you didn't play the part as a father,
بما أنك لم تؤدي دورك كأب
Yi Heon lived in pain because of her.
عاش (يي هيون) في ألم بسببها
Sir.
سيدي
It's me, Mi Kyung.
هذه أنا، (مي كيونغ)
Since I was hired as your secretary,
منذ أن عُينت كمساعدة لك...
I worked for you for over ten years,
عملت لصالحك لأكثر من عشر سنوات
cleaning up the mess your wife, Song Mi Sun, and he made!
نظفت الفوضى التي سببتها زوجتك، (سونغ مي سون)، وهو!
We've been great for many years.
كانت علاقتنا رائعة لعدة سنوات
You said I was the only one you got.
قلت إنني أفضل مساعدة
Seeing how much you got worked up, it's all true.
نظراً إلى انزعاجكِ، فإنها الحقيقة
If what you did with the kidnap and the drugs...
إن كُشف أن ما فعلته بشأن الاختطاف والأدوية
are revealed in connection to the OK Construction...
ذو صلة بـ (أو كي) للبناء
Don't you know it's fatal?
فسيكون ذلك قاتلاً، ألا تعرفين ذلك؟
Wrong place!
إن مكانكِ خاطئ!
You kneel here.
عليكِ الانحناء هنا
You have to apologize to me.
عليكِ الاعتذار إلي
What are you waiting for?
ماذا تنتظرين؟
Goodness.
عجباً
It slipped.
لقد انزلق
From now on, never come near Mother and Song Yi Heon.
من الآن فصاعداً، لا تقتربي من (سونغ يي هيون) ووالدته
If not, I might really bury you in cement.
قد أدفنكِ في الأسمنت إن فعلتِ ذلك
You.
اسمع
You knew what Mi Kyung feared the most...
أنت تعرف أن أكثر ما تخشاه (مي كيونغ)
was getting abandoned by me.
هو أن أتخلى عنها
So this is how you're getting back at her, isn't it?
لذا هذه طريقتك في الانتقام منها، صحيح؟
Yes. That's my boy.
نعم، هذا هو ابني
I'll register you as my son.
سوف أسجلك على أنك ابني
Did you sleep through the Korean class?
هل نمت في حصص اللغة الكورية؟
Don't you know the meaning of raising someone?
ألا تعرف معنى تربية أحدهم؟
To raise is to grow it by taking care of it.
التربية هي أن يكبر الشخص بالاهتمام
You help...
هي أن تساعد...
a child so that he can grow into a good, truthful adult.
طفلاً حتى يكبر ويصبح رجلاً صالحاً وصادقاً
That is the meaning of raising a child.
هذا هو معنى تربية الطفل
If you were to abandon him once you don't need him,
إن كنت ستتخلى عنه عندما لا تحتاج إليه...
you can't call yourself a parent.
فلا تدعو نفسك بالأب
Right. Good job.
نعم، أحسنتما عملاً
I think we're done here. You can leave first.
أعتقد أن عملنا انتهى هنا يمكنكما الذهاب
I'll go home after I make a round.
سأذهب إلى المنزل بعد جولة
You guys should go home.
عليكما الذهاب إلى المنزل
You stay here and help Deuk Pal.
ابقيا هنا وساعدا (ديوك بال)
Take your time.
خذا وقتكما
Do you still read "alligator" as "arigato?"
أما زلت تقرأ كلمة "تمساح" مثل "مرحباً" باليابانية؟
Who...
من...
in the world are you?
أنت؟
Dong Soo. You already know everything.
(دونغ سو)، أنت تعرف كل شيء بالفعل
Did you get home safely?
"هل وصلتِ إلى المنزل بأمان؟"
I stopped by a park on my way home...
توقفت في المنتزه في طريقي
because it was nice and sunny.
لأن الجو جميل ومشمس
Chairman Bae said he'd register me as his son.
قال الرئيس (باي) إنه سيسجلني كابن له
But I said no.
"ولكنني رفضت"
Is it okay?
ألا بأس في ذلك؟
It caught me off guard, but I'm not in shock.
فاجأني هذا، ولكنني لست مصدومة
It's nice to enjoy the sunlight after a long time.
من الجيد الاستمتاع بأشعة الشمس بعد وقت طويل
Actually, I...
في الواقع، أنا...
want to act.
أريد التمثيل
Do you think I can be an actress again?
هل تعتقد أنني سأصبح ممثلة مجدداً؟
Of course, you can. I'll help you.
يمكنكِ ذلك بالتأكيد، سأساعدكِ
I have to take care of some stuff,
يجب أن أتولى بعض الأمور
so you should go to bed first.
لذا عليكِ النوم أولاً
How does it feel to be back?
كيف تشعر بعد عودتك؟
For me,
بالنسبة إلي...
Deuk Pal was always Grade 1.
(ديوك بال) في المركز الأول دائماً
Many things...
تغيرت...
have changed.
أشياء كثيرة
I sort out the bullies.
تخلصت من المتنمرين
I made friends.
كونت صداقات
I punished Lee Mi Kyung and protected Mother.
عاقبت (لي مي كيونغ) وحميت والدتك
I think I've done everything I promised you.
أعتقد أنني أوفيت جميع وعودي
Aren't I amazing?
ألست مذهلاً؟
Don't talk about killing yourself anymore.
لا تفكر في قتل نفسك مجدداً
Live fully as Song Yi Heon.
عش حياة كاملة بصفتك (سونغ يي هيون)
So that my efforts won't go to waste.
حتى لا تضيع جهودي
You didn't get into college.
لم تدخل الجامعة
That's...
هذا...
because you came back too early.
لأنك عدت باكراً جداً
After deciding which college and major you want,
بعد اختيار الكلية والتخصص الذي تريده
you should go to college.
عليك دخول الجامعة
How much time...
كم لدينا...
do we have?
من الوقت؟
A week.
لدينا أسبوع
After a week,
بعد أسبوع...
I'll return to my place, then.
سأعود إلى مكاني
I'm glad I can prepare myself for it.
يسعدني أنني أستطيع الاستعداد لذلك
I'll get things in order and hand them over properly.
سأرتب الأمور، وأسلمها على نحو لائق
Don't forget that you're a senior. Focus on studying.
لا تنس أنك في المرحلة الأخيرة، ركز على الدراسة
(Dong Soo)
"(دونغ سو)"
Why aren't you picking up?
لمَ لا تجيب؟
Are you avoiding him?
هل تتجنبه؟
Are you going to leave him without telling him?
هل ستتركه من دون أن تخبره؟
Aren't you going to tell Se Kyung either?
ألن تخبر (سي كيونغ) أيضاً؟
If I try to explain it to Se Kyung, he'll know who I am.
إن حاولت الشرح لـ (سي كيونغ) سيعرف من أكون
Well...
لذا...
He doesn't have to feel sad because of an old guy, does he?
يجب ألا يحزن بسبب رجل عجوز، صحيح؟
Even at this age,
حتى من هذا السن...
it's hard to say goodbye.
الوداع أمر صعب
(Hansong High School)
"مدرسة (هانسونغ) الثانوية"
Hey, are you all right?
هل أنت بخير؟
I was worried about you.
قلقت بشأنك
Did you hear it from Se Kyung?
هل عرفتم من (سي كيونغ)؟
Everything is okay now. Those boys will go to juvie.
كل شيء بخير، سيدخلون سجن الأحداث
I know you had a tough time,
أعرف أنك مررت بوقت عصيب
but Min Ji won't forgive you easily.
ولكن (مين جي) لن تسامحك بسهولة
You told her she had a big face.
أخبرتها أن لها وجهاً كبيراً
Do you know how hard it was to comfort her that day?
هل تعرف كم كانت مواساتها صعبة ذلك اليوم؟
Wait. When did I say Min Ji had a big face?
مهلاً، متى قلت إن وجه (مين جي) كبير؟
I just said Seol Hee's face was smaller.
قلت إن وجه (سول هي) أصغر فحسب
Hey, that's the same thing.
إنه الأمر ذاته
Well, what I meant to say was...
حسناً، ما قصدت قوله هو...
Though it's true that Seol Hee has a smaller face,
مع أن وجه (سول هي) أصغر...
she's not my type.
ولكنها ليست نوعي المفضل
I like the ones with well-defined features Min Ji.
يعجبني الأشخاص ذوي الملامح المحددة
That's my type.
ذلك هو نوعي المفضل
Okay.
حسناً
I'll accept your apology because I'm awesome.
سأقبل اعتذارك لأنني مذهلة
We'll be watching you.
سنراقبك
You really should watch your mouth.
عليك مراقبة كلامك حقاً
Don't worry.
لا تقلقن
A proper high school student who speaks...
سيصل قريباً تلميذ في الثانوية يجيد...
much nicely will be here.
التحدث بلطف أكبر
- What is he talking about? - Whatever.
- عم يتحدث؟ - أياً يكن
Hey, why didn't you answer my calls?
لماذا لم تجب على اتصالاتي؟
Sorry, I was all over the place.
أنا آسف، كنت مشغولاً
What happened?
ماذا حدث؟
This isn't the right place to talk about it.
هذا ليس المكان المناسب للتحدث
Come.
تعال
Hey. You're possessed, aren't you?
أنت ممسوس، صحيح؟
I mean you look the same.
أقصد أن شكلك لم يتغير
The DNA test result also said you were Song Yi Heon.
ويظهر تحليل الحمض النووي أنك (سونغ يي هيون)
Your soul went into Yi Heon's body, didn't it?
دخلت روحك جسد (يي هيون)، صحيح؟
Hey, how would I know?
مهلاً، كيف سأعرف هذا؟
I didn't know what happened to me either.
أنا لا أعرف ما أصابني أيضاً
So, I'm just going with the flow right now.
لذا أسير مع التيار الآن
Hey. The teacher called me.
إن المعلمة تناديني
I should get going.
يجب أن أذهب
Hey.
مهلاً
(For using violence against classmate, 5 seniors are expelled.)
"طُرد خمسة تلاميذ لأنهم عنفوا زميلهم"
- They deserve to be expelled. - They're finally kicked out.
- إنهم يستحقون الطرد - طُردوا أخيراً
What they did calls for an expulsion.
يستدعي ما فعلوه الطرد
I wanted them to be expelled.
أردتهم أن يُطردوا
Aren't you going to apologize to me?
ألن تعتذر إلي؟
Actually,
في الواقع...
for spreading...
لأنني...
the rumour that you bullied others,
نشرت شائعة أنك تتنمر على الآخرين
and for telling Se Kyung's father about you,
ولأنني أخبرت والد (سي كيونغ) عنك...
I wanted to apologize, but I couldn't get the chance.
أردت الاعتذار، ولكنني لم أجد فرصة
I'm sorry about everything.
أنا آسف بشأن كل شيء
Take your phone out.
أخرج هاتفك
Erase Se Kyung's father's number...
احذف رقم والد (سي كيونغ)
and apologize to Se Kyung too.
واعتذر لـ (سي كيونغ) أيضاً
(Se Kyung's father)
"والد (سي كيونغ)"
(Do you want to move this contact to trash?)
"هل تريد حذف هذا الرقم؟"
Be nice to Se Kyung when I'm gone.
عامل (سي كيونغ) بلطف بعد رحيلي
Don't treat him like a servant.
لا تعامله كالخادم
Be sincerely nice to him...
عامله بصدق...
as his friend.
كصديق
Can I be friends with you too?
هلا نصبح صديقين؟
Forget it.
انس الأمر
You and Yi Heon don't have the same vibe.
أنت و(يي هيون) لا تنسجمان
Now, you can order everything you want.
حسناً، يمكنكِ طلب ما تريدين
Should we get a couple's combo?
هل نأخذ مجموعة الأحباء؟
(A couple's combo)
"مجموعة الأحباء"
Yes. Sure.
نعم، بالتأكيد
One couple's combo, please.
مجموعة أحباء من فضلكِ
Please enjoy.
استمتعا
If we're having a couple's combo,
إن كنا نتناول مجموعة الأحباء...
does it make us a couple?
هل يجعلنا هذا حبيبين؟
No. You can order it when you're not a couple.
لا، يمكنكِ طلبه وإن كنتِ وحدكِ
I'm saying that I have feelings for you.
أقصد أنني معجبة بك
What?
ماذا؟
Thank you.
شكراً لكِ
Can you...
هل...
wait for two days?
يمكنكِ الانتظار ليومين؟
I'll give you an answer in two days.
سأعطيكِ إجابة بعد يومين
In two days?
بعد يومين؟
Okay. I'll wait, then.
حسناً، سأنتظر إذاً
How could you...
كيف يمكنك...
pass along such a thing to me?
منحي شيئاً كهذا؟
I'm not passing along anything. The decision was yours to take.
أنا لا أمنحك شيئاً، إنه قرارك
Going out with a girlfriend and making new friends.
الخروج مع حبيبة وتكوين صداقات
They are all for you to decide.
أنت من يقرر كل شيء
It's because it's your life.
إنها حياتك
Tomorrow is your last day.
غداً هو يومك الأخير
Shouldn't you spend the last day with Se Kyung?
أليس عليك قضاء يومك الأخير مع (سي كيونغ)؟
He must be waiting for you to tell him the truth.
إنه ينتظرك لتخبره الحقيقة
It'll be better...
من الأفضل...
if he doesn't know.
ألا يعلم
(Dong Soo)
"(دونغ سو)"
What time did you get in last night?
متى دخلت ليلة أمس؟
I had a part-time job.
حصلت على عمل جزئي
A part-time job? You're a high school senior.
عمل جزئي؟ أنت تلميذ ثانوية
Are you out of your mind?
هل فقدت عقلك؟
I can still get into a good college even if I have to work part-time.
يمكنني دخول جامعة جيدة وإن عملت بدوام جزئي
And I get the feeling I must be financially independent from you,
وأشعر أن عليّ الاستقلال مادياً عنك
so you will come to acknowledge my independence sooner.
حتى تعترف باستقلالي في وقت أبكر
Acknowledge?
أعترف؟
Do you really expect me to acknowledge your independence...
هل تتوقع مني الاعتراف باستقلالك...
when you're still friends with that lowlife?
بينما ما تزال صديقاً لذلك الحثالة؟
He's not a lowlife. His name is Song Yi Heon.
إنه ليس حثالة، اسمه (سونغ يي هيون)
Besides, he's my best friend.
ثم إنه صديقي المقرب
Don't speak badly of him.
لا تتحدث بالسوء عنه
I'm going to work.
سأذهب إلى العمل
I'm here to apologize.
أتيت للاعتذار
I didn't know you were capable of that.
لم أعرف أنك قادر على ذلك
Song Yi Heon told me to apologize to you.
طلب مني (يي هيون) الاعتذار إليك
He said I should genuinely treat you like a friend,
قال إن عليّ معاملتك كصديق
instead of trying to use you.
عوضاً عن استغلالك
I really want to remain friends with you.
أريد الحفاظ على صداقتنا حقاً
I'll think about it.
سأفكر في الأمر
By the way, it's about Song Yi Heon.
بالمناسبة، بشأن (سونغ يي هيون)...
What about him?
ما الأمر؟
Is he transferring to another school?
هل سينتقل إلى مدرسة أخرى؟
Transfer?
سينتقل؟
I didn't think much of it then.
"لم أفكر في الأمر كثيراً"
But he asked me to take care of you...
"ولكنه طلب مني الاعتناء بك..."
once he was gone.
"بعد رحيله"
What's wrong?
ما الخطب؟
Are you back?
هل عدت؟
Is Yi Heon back?
هل عاد (يي هيون)؟
He came back, but you didn't tell me on purpose. Isn't that it?
لقد عاد، ولكنك لم تخبرني عمداً، صحيح؟
When you knew how worried I had been!
بينما تعرف كم كنت قلقاً!
Let's go.
فلنذهب
I'll give you the answers to all of your questions.
سأمنحك إجابات عن أسئلتك كلها
What are we doing here?
ماذا نفعل هنا؟
You said you would give me answers.
قلت إنك ستمنحني إجابات
(The late Kim Deuk Pal)
"(كيم ديوك بال) الراحل"
That's me.
هذا أنا
"Kim Deuk Pal."
(كيم ديوك بال)
You were born in 1977.
ولدت في 1977
Yes, I'm dead.
نعم، أنا ميت
I tried to save Song Yi Heon...
حاولت إنقاذ (سونغ يي هيون)
when he jumped off the pedestrian overpass.
عندما قفز من جسر المشاة
I think that's when my spirit went into Song Yi Heon's body.
أعتقد أن روحي دخلت جسده آنذاك
I guess it's similar to a spirit...
أعتقد أن روحي...
taking over a body.
سيطرت على جسده
So physically, you're dead.
إن جسدك ميت إذاً
But once Yi Heon's spirit comes back,
ولكن عندما تعود روح (يي هيون)...
you have no place to go.
لن يكون لديك مكان لتذهب إليه
I don't.
هذا صحيح
Naturally, I'll die.
لذا سأموت
That's why I couldn't tell you.
لهذا لم أستطع إخبارك
I thought that once Yi Heon came back,
اعتقدت أنه حالما يعود (يي هيون)...
the joy of seeing your friend again...
قد تكون متعة رؤية صديقك مجدداً....
might be able to make the sadness go away...
قادرة على إزالة الحزن
because we would look the same.
لأن شكله لن يتغير
Then why are you telling me the truth now?
لمَ تخبرني الحقيقة الآن إذاً؟
You would have definitely tried something...
لا بد من أنك جربت شيئاً ما
after hearing everything from Jae Hoon.
بعد سماع كل شيء من (جاي هون)
You would have probably tried to verify that the real Yi Heon...
على الأرجح أنك ستحاول التحقق من عودة
came back.
(سونغ يي هيون)
Just like now.
كما تفعل الآن
Just like now?
كما أفعل الآن؟
Song Yi Heon is back.
عاد (سونغ يي هيون)
Are you really...
هل أنت...
Yi Heon?
(يي هيون) حقاً؟
Can Se Kyung also see his spirit?
هل يستطيع (سي كيونغ) رؤية روحه أيضاً؟
(Emergency transport)
"نقل الطوارئ"
That's why on the bus...
لهذا في الحافلة...
I'm craving a shot of soju on a day like today.
أنا أشتهي كأس (سوجو) في يوم كهذا
My dear nephew.
ابن أخي العزيز
Why have you been dodging our calls lately?
لمَ كنت تتجاهل اتصالاتنا مؤخراً؟
He wanted to come and see you,
أراد المجيء لرؤيتك
but I stopped him because I thought you were studying for your exam.
ولكنني منعته لأنني اعتقدت أنك تدرس للامتحان
I told him that you would call him once the exam was over.
أخبرته أنك ستتصل به حالما ينتهي الامتحان
But funny running into you here.
ولكن من المضحك مصادفتك هنا
We must have been...
لا بد من أننا...
on the same "website."
في الموقع ذاته
Gosh.
عجباً
You mean "on the same page."
أنت تقصد أننا متوافقون
Don't you remember? Our boss told us to study.
ألا تتذكر؟ طلب منا الزعيم الدراسة
"On the same page."
نحن متوافقون
Let's go and have soju.
فلنشرب الـ (سوجو)
Sir. Is it okay for a student to drink soju, though?
سيدي، ألا بأس أن يشرب تلميذ الـ (سوجو)؟
Let's go.
فلنذهب
I only brought two bottles.
اشتريت زجاجتين فقط
That night,
تلك الليلة...
you decided to jump off the pedestrian overpass.
قررت القفز من جسر المشاة
That's all my fault.
إنها غلطتي
I didn't want to get hurt.
لم أرد الإصابة بأذى
So I pushed you to the overpass.
لذا دفعتك إلى الجسر
I sincerely want to apologize to you.
أود الاعتذار إليك بصدق
I'm really scared.
أنا خائف حقاً
I feel suffocated.
أنا أشعر بالاختناق
Could you help me?
هلا تساعدني؟
I know you can help me.
أعرف أنك تستطيع مساعدتي
Why should I get involved? This is your problem.
لم قد أتورط؟ إنها مشكلتك
Tell your parents.
أخبر والديك
Or if you can't, transfer to another school.
أو انتقل إلى مدرسة أخرى
No. Transferring to a new school won't solve anything.
لا، لن يحل الانتقال المشكلة
I made up my mind.
لقد اتخذت قراري
I'll report them to the school violence committee.
سأبلغ هيئة العنف المدرسي عنهم
I'll also report them to the police.
وسأبلغ الشرطة أيضاً
So I'll make Jae Min and his friends face criminal punishment.
وسأجعل (جاي مين) ورفاقه يواجهون العقاب الجنائي
So...
لذا...
could you tell your father?
هلا تخبر والدك؟
Your father is a prosecutor.
إن والدك مدع عام
No.
لا
To tell you the truth, I was angry when I saw you that night.
في الحقيقة، كنت غاضباً عندما رأيتك تلك الليلة
"Why can't he fight back?"
لمَ لا يستطيع المواجهة؟
"I helped him. But why is he being so pathetic?"
لقد ساعدته، لمَ هو مثير للشفقة؟
Then I realized that I couldn't fight back to my dad just like you.
ثم أدركت أنني لم أستطع مواجهة أبي مثلك
Seeing you getting beaten up, unable to fight back...
رؤيتك تُضرب وعدم قدرتك على الرد...
reminded me of myself.
ذكرتني بنفسي
I think that made me angry.
أعتقد أن ذلك أغضبني
Then...
إذاً...
I will expose your true nature to other people.
سأفضح طبيعتك الحقيقية أمام الناس
You are kind to them.
أنت تعاملهم بلطف
You act cheerful and smile at them.
أنت تتظاهر بالمتعة، وتبتسم أمامهم
But that's all fake.
ولكن هذا مزيف
What's your point?
ماذا تقصد؟
When Jae Hoon broke his ankle in the gym that day,
عندما كسر (جاي هون) كاحله في النادي ذلك اليوم
you were the first one to see him. I'm sure of it.
كنت أول من رآه، أنا واثق من ذلك
But you acted as if you didn't see that.
ولكنك تظاهرت بأنك لم تره
Jae Hoon might think of you as a true friend.
يعتقد (جاي هون) أنك صديق حقيقي
But you don't.
ولكنك لست كذلك
You just despise and hate people.
أنت تبغض وتكره الناس فقط
That's who you are.
هذه حقيقتك
No one had seen my worst side except for you.
لم ير أحد غيرك جانبي السيئ
For the first time, I felt like I was naked.
لأول مرة، شعرت أنني عار
So I might have been harsher on you than I wanted to.
لذا عاملتك بقسوة أكبر مما أردت
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف
No.
لا
I was cruel to you that night too.
عاملتك بقسوة تلك الليلة
But still. I shouldn't have been mean to you...
مع ذلك، يجب ألا أعاملك بلؤم...
when you were desperately asking for my help.
عندما تطلب مساعدتي بيأس
Please help me.
ساعدني من فضلك
I'm begging you.
أنا أتوسل إليك
If you tell your father,
إن أخبرت والدك...
they might...
قد...
confess what they've done.
يعترفون بما فعلوه
When I reported them for school violence,
عندما أبلغت هيئة العنف المدرسي
you said they didn't bully you.
قلت إنهم لم يتنمروا عليك
Part of it is your fault.
إنها غلطتك نوعاً ما
No. It's all your fault.
لا، إنها غلطتك بالتأكيد
Se Kyung.
(سي كيونغ)
This isn't your fault.
هذه ليست غلطتك
It would have been great if I could fight back...
سيكون من الرائع أن تواجه...
just like Mr. Kim Deuk Pal or the new you.
مثل السيد (كيم ديوك بال) أو شخصيتك الجديدة
Facing my problem head-on...
إن مواجهة مشكلاتي...
would have been nice even if I failed.
أفضل وإن فشلت
Back then, I had no idea what I was supposed to do.
لم أعرف ما عليّ فعله آنذاك
But now, I know.
ولكنني أعرف الآن
I learned it from Yi Heon.
تعلمت ذلك من (يي هيون)
I'll be the one helping you, not my father.
أنا من سيساعدك، وليس أبي
And I'll be your true friend.
وسأكون صديقك الحقيقي
Yes.
نعم
Don't let your father hurt you anymore.
لا تسمح لوالدك في إزعاجك بعد الآن
Hang in there.
استجمع قواك
I forgive you.
أنا أسامحك
No. I've already forgiven you.
لا، سامحتك بالفعل
Thank you for telling me that you would be...
شكراً لأنك أخبرتني أنك ستصبح...
my friend.
صديقي
Why didn't you tell me sooner?
لماذا لم تخبرني سابقاً؟
"I'm Deuk Pal."
أنا (ديوك بال)
"I'm your boss."
أنا زعيمك
Why didn't you tell me?
لماذا لم تخبرني؟
I'm already dead.
أنا ميت بالفعل
I didn't want there to be a second funeral...
لم أرد إقامة جنازة أخرى...
for my dead spirit.
لروحي الميتة
That would have been too cruel for you guys.
سيكون ذلك مؤلماً لكما
Dong Soo.
(دونغ سو)
Thank you for staying loyal to me...
شكراً لأنك بقيت وفياً لي...
for all these years.
طوال تلك السنوات
I was happy...
سعدت...
that I got to work under you, sir.
بالعمل لصالحك، سيدي
In whatever body or form you come back,
أياً كان الجسد أو الهيئة اللذان تعود بهما...
I will never forget you.
لن أنساك أبداً
You should go now.
يجب أن تذهب الآن
You must go first for me to leave at peace.
يجب أن تذهب أولاً لأغادر بسلام
Out of...
من بين...
all the people I've met, you were the most admirable friend...
جميع الناس الذين قابلتهم أنت هو الصديق الأفضل
and adult.
وأفضل بالغ
A friend I wish I had by my side.
أنت صديق رغبت في وجوده في جانبي
A dear friend like that.
صديق عزيز مثلك
I was happy that you were my friend too.
يسعدني أنك صديقي أيضاً
You can be a much better adult than me.
يمكنك أن تصبح بالغاً أفضل مني بكثير
Don't doubt yourself and keep pushing forward.
لا تشك في نفسك وامض قدماً
Your parents must be waiting.
إن والديك في انتظارك
Sir, you should go back.
سيدي، يجب أن تعود
Go back where?
إلى أين؟
You know where to go.
أنت تعرف إلى أين ستذهب
I don't have any desires left in this life.
ليست لدي رغبات أخرى في هذه الحياة
When I jumped off the pedestrian overpass,
عندما قفزت من جسر المشاة...
I had let go of everything.
تخليت عن كل شيء
But still.
مع ذلك...
I can't steal your life.
لا يمكنني سرقة حياتك
I'm tired.
أنا متعب
I don't have any energy left to live my life.
لم تبق لدي أي طاقة لأعيش حياتي
But thanks to you,
ولكن بفضلك...
I was happy to see a smile on my face.
شعرت بالسعادة لأنني رأيت ابتسامة على وجهي
If someone could be happy in my body,
إن استطاع أحدهم العيش بسعادة في جسدي...
that would be enough to make me happy.
فسيكون ذلك كافياً لإسعادي
- Hello. - Hello.
- مرحباً
You really are the school president.
أنت رئيس المدرسة فعلاً
You are still popular.
ما تزال مشهوراً
What are you still doing here?
ماذا تفعل هنا؟
We go to the same school.
نحن في المدرسة ذاتها
Isn't it natural to run into each other?
أليس من الطبيعي أن نصادف بعضنا بعضاً؟
No. Wasn't your first period your major class?
لا، أليست فترتك الأولى هي صف التخصص؟
I was watching the soccer game late last night. So I overslept.
شاهدت كرة القدم حتى وقت متأخر ليلة أمس، لذا نمت كثيراً
It's not too late. Attend the class now.
لم يتأخر الوقت، اذهب إلى صفك
Hey, it's already too late.
تأخر الوقت بالفعل
How could you still act like my tutor even in college?
كيف تتصرف كمعلمي حتى في الجامعة؟
This guy completely changed now that he's in college.
تغير هذا الشاب كلياً بعد دخول الجامعة
Yi Heon should have stayed, not you.
كان يجب أن يبقى (يي هيون)، وليس أنت
Hey, do you want to go on a group blind date?
هل تريد الخروج في موعد جماعي مُدبر؟
I need to study for my exam.
يجب أن أدرس للامتحان
Hey. Youth is there to be enjoyed.
إن الهدف من الشباب هو الاستمتاع
That old saying only worked when you went to school, old man.
كان هذا المثل صحيحاً عندما كنت تذهب إلى المدرسة أيها العجوز
Kids these days are busy...
أطفال هذه الأيام مشغولون
learning foreign languages and improving their skill set.
بتعلم لغات أجنبية وتطوير مهاراتهم
How come you're the only one, taking it easy, old man?
لمَ أنت الوحيد الذي يستخف بالأمر أيها العجوز؟
Hey, let's go to Jong Cheol's cafe and study there.
فلنذهب إلى مقهى (جونغ تشول) ولندرس هناك
We can have a cup of coffee.
يمكننا شرب كوب قهوة
You want to hang out with the uncles again, don't you?
أنت تريد الخروج مع عميك مجدداً، صحيح؟
Hang out with them?
الخروج معهما؟
They want to take the GED,
يريدان اجتياز اختبار الثقافة العامة
so I'm going there to help them. You know?
لذا سأذهب لمساعدتهما، حسناً؟
Gosh.
عجباً
- Do you want to come with me? - Forget it.
- هل تريد مرافقتي؟ - انس الأمر
Come on. Let's go.
هيا، فلنذهب
- Come with me. Let's go. - I have to study.
- تعال معي، فلنذهب - يجب أن أدرس
Hey. Why don't we go and have makgeolli?
لمَ لا نذهب لشرب (ماكغيولي)؟
We can go to a bar in front of the school.
فلنذهب إلى حانة قريبة من المدرسة
How about makgeolli? Yes?
ماذا عن (ماكغيولي)؟ حسناً؟
(Thank you for watching High School Return of a Gangster.)
"شكراً لمشاهدتكم مسلسل انتقام طالب"